# **GESER DUGAROV, Ph.D.**

email: geserdugarov@gmail.com

**mobile**: +7-913-703-1014

languages: English (advanced), Russian (native)

**location**: Novosibirsk, Russia

#### **SUMMARY**

Data-driven R&D in the IT industry. Wide experience in fundamental research (12 yrs) and project management (6 yrs). Holds a degree of a Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.) in Geophysics. Author and coauthor of more than 50 publications.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Python, Docker, Git, Linux, Matlab

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

ML Research Engineer, <u>Digital Research</u> (spinoff of <u>Digital Clouds</u>)

II/2022 - current

• Vehicles monitoring (based on computer vision) in the construction industry. Team leader role.

### Senior Researcher.

**Trofimuk Institute of Petroleum Geology and Geophysics** 

X/2009 – current

- Transferred new technology of fractures parameters estimation from fundamental research to business. Team leader role.
- 5 years in a row of personal projects supporting by main foundations (2017-2021).
- 4 graduate students: 3 MSc (2022\*2, 2020), 1 BSc (2020).
- "The best young researcher in Earth science organizations" award (2019).

Research Associate (II/2014 – IV/2019), Research Assistant (X/2009 – II/2014)

#### **EDUCATION**

PhD, Geophysics, X/2009 – XII/2013

Trofimuk Institute of Petroleum Geology and Geophysics SB RAS

(4 years)

MSc, Computational and Applied Mathematics,

IX/2004 - VI/2009

Novosibirsk State University

(5 years)

## **CERTIFICATES**

- Deep Learning Specialization, Coursera (2021).
- Machine Learning, Coursera (2021).

#### **PROJECTS**

- XII/2019 VIII/2021 AVAZ inversion of local object anisotropy parameters from 3D seismic data *Role*: **project manager**. *Team size*: 7. Customer: NTC NIS-Naftagas, Serbia.
- VII/2019 VI/2021 Acoustic properties and internal structure of hydrate-bearing coal samples *Role*: **head of the project**. *Team size*: 5. Supported by RSF, grant No. <u>19-77-00068</u>.

# **HONORS AND AWARDS**

- Trofimuk Memorial Medal Award (2021).
- "The best young researcher in Earth science organizations" (2019).

### **HOBBIES**

- Going to the gym on a regular basis (since 2019).
- Reading developmental psychology and business management books.

Updated: 18.08.2022, the last version

